# Amalia Sörlien

# **EDUCATION**

# **Design and Product Development**

Linköping University | 2013- 2018 M.Sc in Engineering

The education is as much about design as solving problems and project management. I have both technical and design knowledge throughout the whole product development process, from idea to finished product.

# Industrial Design Engineering

San Diego State University | 2016

I started my masters degree with one semester at San Diego State University.

## COMPETENCES

#### Visualization

Photoshop

Illustrator

Figma

Balsamiq

## Development

HTML

CSS

Java Script

# Languages

Swedish

English

#### Soft skills

**Ambitious** 

Fast learner

Team player

Curious

Keen eye for details

# **PROFILE**

I see myself as a designer and a creative engineer. As a designer, I have a profound interest in human-centred design and user experiences. With a background as an engineer I enjoy problem-solving and to find smart and feasible solutions.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Software Component Owner

Volvo Group Trucks Technology | 2020- present

I am working in a team that develop and maintain our Development Portal for 3:rd party applications. My responsibility is to manage these applications through the complete life cycle, from initiation to over the air deployment. As a single point of contact towards stakeholders for 3:rd party applications, I am in continuous collaborations with a cross-functional and global network.

# Human Machine Interface Engineer

Volvo Group Trucks Technology | 2018- 2020

The daily work included collaboration with different stakeholders, such as UX-designers and developers, to develop and maintain the in-house Android based entertainment system. I delivered HMI specifications to my team and was responsible for HMI requirements. In this role, it was important to effectively communicate with stakeholders and coordinate the flow of information in order to work successfully.

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

# **Dynamic Web Application**

University course for HTML, CSS and Java Script development | 2019

## Advanced Engineering Project

HMI asset in a project for Volvo GTT | 2019

# First Aid Helper

Volvo GTT | 2019

## **SAFe Training**

Participated in a two-day certified SAFe agile training | 2019

#### Driver's License B

2012







